# GuilhermeDeMaio

Software Developer

#### contact

São Paulo - Brasil

+55 11 9 8393 2639

**S** quilherme nirev guilherme@nirev.org https://nirev.dev

**O**/nirev

**y**/nirev

**in**/nirev

#### languages

native portuguese fluent english basic french

## programming

Elixir, Java, Ruby, Javascript, C, Python, HTML, css, bash, Kafka, Spark, docker, monitoring tools

#### interests

distributed systems, making a better world, data structures, music, martial arts, science fiction books

## about me

I've been developing software for over 10 years, from web apps to embedded platforms. During this time I've come to believe: - Empathy first, always - Trust is key - Less is more

On the tech side of things, I'm more of a backend/operations type, but I do dabble a bit on the frontend. I enjoy taking part and ownership of where and how applications are deployed and monitored.

I take pride in being part of team. I enjoy giving talks and getting to know people at conferences. I've been a team lead before, and I dislike the term "soft skills". Once you're in a position as such, those so called "soft" skills are exactly what is most important.

# recent experience

September 2015 - \*

Senior Software Engineer at XERPA

São Paulo - Brazil

I joined the company as their first employee to help build the SaaS platform tackling HR bureaucracy in Brazil. We started from day-0 with Elixir and Phoenix on the backend, with the frontend initially in simple html/css/jquery. We eventually migrated the frontend to ClojureScript using a GraphQL API.

Among things I took part are:

- Bootstrapped the platform using Elixir, Phoenix, PostgreSQL, Terraform and Ansible
- Built libraries for:
- Authentication and Authorization
- Indexing things to ElasticSearch, as well as defining mappings
- Resizing and manipulating images
- Integrating with payment gateways
- Defining and prioritizing features together with product and business/sales teams.
- Interviewing "beta" clients to get a better understanding of the problems we needed to solve.
- Collaborating heavily with Customer Success team to help streamline client usage after signup, focusing on quickly solving bugs and improving user experience
- Using OCR to identify unique numbers in PDFs, built a document distribution feature which greatly improved sales and customer satisfaction.

November 2012 – September 2015

#### Team Lead (Search and Analytics) at Elo7

São Paulo - Brazil

A marketplace with high traffic and transaction volume. The stack was based on Java, Ruby and Scala on AWS infrastructure. A fast paced environment, with agile practices, and focusing on delivering fast with quality. We measured and logged using StatsD, Graphite, and NewRelic, and deployed constantly. I was leading the Search and Analytics Team: a small team using Solr, Kafka and Spark to improve search and real time reports, and responsible for its infrastructure and pipeline tools.

## past experiences details available upon request

04/2012 to 10/2012 - Intern at INRIA Paris-Roquencourt	Paris - France
03/2011 to 09/2012 - Undergrad Researcher at USP - CHOReOS project	São Paulo - Brazil
08/2010 to 02/2011 - Software Developer (C/C++) at RR Sistema	Vitória/ES - Brazil
01/2009 to 12/2010 - Undergrad Intern at Multimedia and Network Research Lab	Vitória/ES - Brazil
08/2008 to 12/2008 - Undergrad Intern at LASSY	University of Luxembourg - LU
03/2007 to 12/2007 - Undergrad Intern at NINFA laboratory	Vitória/ES - Brazil
09/2006 to 03/2007 - PHP Developer at Lettera Soluções	Vitória/ES - Brazil

# education

2011–2014 Master in Computer Science University of São Paulo - Brazil 2005–2010 B.Sc. in Computer Science Federal University of Espírito Santo - Brazil